FULL-STACK DEVELOPER

Kenneth MacLean

Toronto, ON

Phone: 647-381-7742 | Email: Kenneth.maclean84@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/kenmaclean7742 | GitHub: https:// github.com/DoshPocket | Portfolio: https://doshpocket.github.io/my-portfoliowebapp/

PROFILE

With backgrounds in education and finance, ambitious full-stack web developer who develops from a responsive and accessibility-first approach in order to best build creative applications defined by streamlined user experiences. Have built applications both solo and among other developers in an agile workspace as lead engineer, concept creator, and collaborator.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: SQL, HTML, CSS, Javascript, React

Web Development: Bootstrap, Tailwind, Semantic UI, jQuery, React, Node.js, Express,

MongoDB, Graphql, Inquirer, Jest

Dev-op Tools: GitHub, Git, Heroku

PROJECTS

HIVEMIND | JAVASCRIPT HTML CSS HANDLEBARS ANIME.JS DARKMODE.JS HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/DOSHPOCKET/HIVE-MIND | HTTPS://
HIVEMIND-442.HEROKUAPP.COM/

As lead engineer of a development team of four and concept creator, built a web application that assists a busy avid dater in planning their upcoming dates. The application randomly selects an activity and offers the user a keyword search tied to a relevant API. The user can save the results to an 'upcoming dates' list.

ROMANTIC DATE PLANNER | JAVASCRIPT HTML CSS BOOTSTRAP TAILWIND HTTPS://DOSHPOCKET.GITHUB.IO/ROMANTIC-DATE-PLANNER/

As lead engineer of a development team of four and concept creator, built a web application that assists a busy avid dater in planning their upcoming dates. The application randomly selects an activity and offers the user a keyword search tied to a relevant API. The user can save the results to an 'upcoming dates' list.

SOCIAL NETWORK API | JAVASCRIPT HTML MONGOOSE
HTTPS://GITHUB.COM/DOSHPOCKET/SOCIAL-NETWORK-API

A social network API that utilizes MongooseDB to provide the user with functional and modularized routes that allow for full CRUD operations for new users, thoughts, reactions and the ability to add and remove friends from their personal networks. Responsible for all aspects of this project.

EXPERIENCE

CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE, RBC DIRECT INVESTING; TORONTO, ON – 2015-2022

Handled client inquiries while managing and organizing data across multiple systems and databases. Responsible for keeping knowledge and understanding up to date on the latest financial news and technology.

ASSISTANT LANGUAGE TEACHER, INTERAC, JAPAN; KAWASAKI, JAPAN – 2011-2013 Coordinated with myriad local teachers to develop curriculum and deliver engaging ESL lessons to grade five and six students. Managed large groups of students to complete complex tasks and assignments.

ENGLISH LANGUAGE INSTRUCTOR, BERLITZ, JAPAN; TOKYO, JAPAN – 2007-2013 Tailored lesson content to individual student needs and facilitated kids lessons training sessions for fellow employees in order to strengthen unit kids lessons delivery.

EDUCATION

University of Toronto, Toronto, ON - Full Stack Boot Camp Certificate University of Toronto, Toronto, ON - Bachelor of Education University of Guelph, Guelph, ON - Bachelor of Arts, English